A Guide to the Headquarters Papers of Brigadier-General John Forbes Relating to the Expedition against Fort Duquesne in 1758
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Lancaster, Adam Hoops to [Forbes]. Docketed: "Ad: Hoops letter about forrage &:c", 1758 April 8; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- Williamsburg, Bosomworth to Forbes. Docketed: "Capt. Bosomworth Williamsburgh Aprile 8th", 1758 April 8; LS, 4 p. (Box Oversize)
- Williamsburg, John Blair to Bosomworth. Docketed: "Presidt Blair to Capt. Bosomworth", 1758 April 8; L (copy), 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- Lancaster, Hoops to Robert Thompson, 1758 April 9; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, St. Clair to Forbes. Docketed: "Sir John St Clair Philadelph: Aprile 9th [R: 11]th", 1758 April 9; LS, 4 p. (Box Box 2)
- (in third person) New York, Abercrombie to Forbes. Docketed: "Capt Abercromby abt Sir Jno St Clair N.Y: Aprile 10th", [1758] April 10; L, 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- Williamsburg, John Blair to Bosomworth. Docketed: "The President of Virginia to Capt Bosomworth 10th April 1758", 1758 April 10; L (copy), 3 p. (Box Box 2)
- Fort Augusta, "Extract of a letter from Lt. Col. Burd..." Docketed: "Intelligence from Col: Burd Apl 13", 1758 April 13; L (copy), 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- New York, Abercromby to Forbes. Docketed: "General Abercromby to B: F-- Aprile 13th Rec'd at 1 o clock", 1758 April 13; LS, 3 p. (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, St. Clair to Forbes. Docketed: "Sir John St Clair Philadelphia April 13th R: 20th", 1758 April 13; LS, 3 p. (Box Box 2)
- New York, Abercromby to John Dagworthy. Docketed: "Copy Genll Abercrombys letter to Capt Dagworthy abt the Maryland Troops. N: York Aprile 14th", 1758 April 14; L (copy), 3 p. (Box Box 2)
- New York, John Appy. "By John Appy Esqr Judge Advocate of all His Majesty's Forces in North America. " Docketed: "Deputation to Act as Judge Advocate April 14th 1758", 1758 April 14; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- New York, James Abercromby & John Appy. "By His Excellency, James Abercromby, Esquire; Colonel of His Majesty's Forty Fourth Regiment of Foote; Colonel in Chief of the Royal American Regiment; Major General; and Commander in Chief of all His Majesty's Forces raised or to be raised in North America..." Docketed: "Warrant empowering B.G. Forbes to call Gen. Courts Martial. April 14th 1758", 1758 April 14; Ms, 3 p. (Box Box 2)
- New York, Christopher Kilby to Joshua Howell. Docketed: "Mr Kilby to Mr Howell N York Aprile 14th", 1758 April 14; L (copy), 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- Williamsburg, John Blair to St. Clair. Docketed: "Mr Presedent Blair to Sir John St Clair Williamsburgh Aprile 15th", 1758 April 15; LS, 3 p. (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, Forbes to Abercromby. Docketed: "Letter to Genll Abercromby Philadelphia Aprile 20th", 1758 April 20; L (copy), 3 p. (Box Box 2)
- Fort Cumberland, John Dagworthy to Sharpe. Docketed: "Capt. Dagworthy to Govr. Sharp", 1758 April 21; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, [Forbes] to Denny. Docketed: "Copy letter to G. Denny", 1758 April 21; L (copy), 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, [Forbes] to Denny, 1758 April 21; AL (draft) (Box Box 2)
  Includes next four items on the same sheet.
- Forbes to Denny, 1758 April 21; LS (copy) (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, Forbes to Denny, 1758 April 20; L (copy) (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, Denny to Thomas Januaryvier, 1758 April 20; L (copy) (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, Forbes, Receipt for Thomas Januaryvier, 1758 April 21; Ms (copy), 4 p. (Box Box 2)
- Fort Loudoun. "Speech of Captain Bosomworth to the Headmen, Chiefs, and Warriors of His Majesty's faithful Friends and allies the Cherokees and Catawbas in Council Assembled at Fort Loudoun in the Dominion of Virginia 21st April 1758" and "The Answer of the 12 Headmen and Warriors...to Captain Bosomworth's Speech...." Docketed: "Captn. Bosomworth's Proceedings with the Indians at Fort Loudoun in Virginia ", 1758 April 21 -23; Ms, 15 p. (Box Box 2)
- Winchester, Bosomworth "A Return of the Southern Indians." Docketed: "A Return of the Southern Indians Winchester 21st April 1758", 1758 April 21; MsS, 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- Winchester, Bosomworth "A Return of the Southern Indians." Docketed: "A Return of the Southern Indians Winchester 21st April 1758", 1758 April 21; Ms (copy), 2 p. (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, Forbes to Abercromby. Docketed: "Copy letter to G: Abercromby Ph: Aprile 22d", 1758 April 22; L (copy), 4 p. (Box Box 2)
- New York, Abercromby to Forbes. Docketed: "Genl Abercromby N York Aprile 22d R- 23d", 1758 April 22; LS, 3 p. (Box Box 2)
- New York, Abercromby to Forbes. Docketed: "Genll Abercromby New York Aprile 24th", 1758 April 24; LS, 3 p. (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, Forbes to Abercromby. Docketed: "Copy Letter to Gen: Abercrom Philadelp: Aprile 24", 1758 April 24; L (copy), 4 p. (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, St. Clair to John Blair. Docketed: "Copy of Sir John St. Clair 's letter to John Blair Esqr. President of Virginia 24th April 1758", 1758 April 24; L (copy), 3 p. (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, St. Clair to Sharpe. Docketed: "Copy of Sir John St. Clair 's letter to Govr. Sharp 24th April 1758", 1758 April 24; L (copy), 3 p. (Box Box 2)
- Philadelphia, Denny to Forbes. Docketed: "Govr. Denny Phi:", 1758 April 25; LS, 3 p. (Box Box 3)
- New York, Abercromby to Forbes. Docketed: "Genll Abercromby N: York Aprile 25th R -- 28th", 1758 April 25; LS, 7 p. (Box Box 3)
- "Sir John St. Clair bart in accot with Joseph Simons. " Docketed: "Things furnished by Mr. Symons for the Army", 1758 April 25 -May 10; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, Denny to Forbes. Docketed: "Message Govr Denny to B: Forbes", 1758 April 26; L (copy), 3 p. (Box Box 3)
- "At a Council of 26th April 1758", 1758 April 26; Ms, 1 p. (Box Box 3)
- Williamsburg, John Blair to [Forbes] Docketed: "Mr Presidt Blair. Virginia Aprile 26", 1758 April 26; LS, 3 p. (Box Box 3)
- Fort Augusta, James Burd to Denny. Docketed: "Extract of a letter from Col: Burd to Governor Denny. 26th April 1758 - Intelligence", 1758 April 26; L (copy), 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Charlestown, William Henry Lyttelton to Forbes. Docketed: "Governor Littleton. So Carolina Aprile 26 Rd: May 5th", 1758 April 26; LS, 3 p. (Box Box 3)
- Charlestown, James Sinclair to St. Clair. Docketed: "Capt St Clair to Sir Jno St Clair So Carolina Aprile 27", 1758 April 26; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- New York, Abercromby to Forbes, Philadelphia. Docketed: "Genll Abercromby N: York Aprile 27th", 1758 April 27; LS, 3 p. (Box Box 3)
- Annapolis, Sharpe to Forbes. Docketed: "Copy of Governour Sharpe's letter to Brigadr. Genll. Forbes 27th April 1758", 1758 April 27; L (copy), 3 p. (Box Box 3)
- Lancaster, Adam Hoops to Joshua Howell. Docketed: "Adam Hoops Letter to Mr Howell", 1758 April 27; L (copy), 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Fort Johnson, Sir William Johnson to Abercromby. Docketed: "Copy of a letter from Sir Willm Johnson to M: Genl: Abercromby", 1758 April 28; L (copy), 9 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, Forbes to Gov. Denny. Docketed: "Copy. Letter General Forbes to Governor Denny. 28th April 1758", 1758 April 28; L (copy), 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- New York. "Copy of an order given out 29th April 1758 New York." Docketed: "Order Relative to Provisions 29th April 1758", 1758 April 29; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- "Copy of Verbal Message of Assembly delivered by two Members the 29 April. 1758 in Answer to General Forbes's letter of the 28." Docketed: "Copy Verbal Message of Assembly 29th. April 1758", 1758 April 29; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Makerstown, George Makdougall to Forbes. Docketed: "Letter Majr. Mc.Dougall Mackerstown 29th April 1758", 1758 April 29; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Keowee in Cherokee, William Byrd to [Forbes?]. Docketed: "Letter Colo. Byrd Keowee in the Cherokee Country 30th April", 1758 April 30; ALS, 4 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, St. Clair to [John] Hunter. Docketed: "Copy of Sir John St. Clair s letter to Col. Hunter of Hampton 30th April 1758", 1758 April 30; L (copy), 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, St. Clair to John Blair. Docketed: "Copy of Sr. John St. Clair s letter to John Blair Esqr. President of Virginia 30th April 1758", 1758 April 30; L (copy), 3 p. (Box Box 3)
- " William West to John Rouse " Docketed: "No. 30 John Rouse ", [1758 May]; Ms (receipt), 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, Forbes to the Provincial Commissioners. Docketed: "Copy Letter to the Pro: Comssnrs May", [1758] May; ALS (draft), 3 p. (Box Box 3)
- William West. "A list of goods bought by Capt. Bosomworth and William West for the Cherokee Indians by order of General Forbes"; "A list of goods bought by Sr. John St. Clair taken from a list...by Capt. Bosomworth." Docketed: "A list of goods for the Cherokee Indians", 1758 May; MsS, 2 p. (Box Oversize)
- Philadelphia, Draper S. Wood to Forbes. "A Calculation of Provisions for six Thousand Men for Three months or 84 Days Philadelphia May 1st 1758." Docketed: "A Calculation of Provisions to serve 6000 men three months May ye. 1st 1758", 1758 May 1; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Williamsburg, John Blair to St. Clair. Docketed: "Presidt Blair to Sir John St. Clair. Williamsb: May 1st", 1758 May 1; LS, 3 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, Abraham Bosomworth to Forbes, "For the better Regulation..." Docketed: "Proposition for Regulating the Indians going to War", 1758 May 2; MsS, 3 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, Forbes to Sharpe. Docketed: "Letter to Govr Sharp. Philad: May 2d 1758", 1758 May 2; AL (draft), 3 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, Forbes, "As two hundred Waggons...rendezvous at Carlisle...." Docketed: "Philad: May 2d", 1758 May 2; AMs (draft), 4 p. (Box Box 3)
- "A List of Necessarys to be provided by each Waggoner." Docketed: "A list of Necessarys to be provided by each Waggoner", [1758 May 2]; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- "By order of General Forbes. Notice is hereby Given that a Number of Waggons will be wanted for his Majestys service...", [1758 May 2]; Ms (draft), 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Lancaster, Adam Hoops to Forbes, Philadelphia. Docketed: "Mr. Hoops Lancaster May 2d", 1758 May 2; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, Forbes to Denny. Docketed: "Letter to Govr Denny Philad: May 4th. J.F:", 1758 May 3; ALS, 3 p. (Box Box 3)
- Thomas Leech, Speaker. "A Message to the Governor from the Assembly" Docketed: "Message to the Goverr Denny from the Assembly--May 3d", 1758 May 3; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- New York, Christopher Kilby to Forbes, Philadelphia. Docketed: "Mr Kilby New York May 3d", 1758 May 3; LS, 3 p. (Box Box 3)
- New York, Abercromby to Forbes. Docketed: "Genll Abercromby's Letter about Provisions and Officers Rations May 4th 1758", 1758 May 4; LS, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, Forbes to Abercromby. Docketed: "Copy Letter to G: Abercromby Philad: May 4th. J F ", 1758 May 4; L (copy), 4 p. (Box Box 3)
- New York, Abercromby to Forbes. Docketed: "Genll Abercromby N. Y: May 4th", 1758 May 4; LS, 4 p. (Box Box 3)
- Shamokin. "Intelligence received from John Hochstattler a Swiss by Nation who was Settled in Berks County Berner Township near Kauffmans Creek & was taken by the Enemy Indians ye. 12th. Octr. & escaped from them & arrived at Shamokin 5th May 1758." Docketed: "Intelligence", 1758 May [5]; Ms, 4 p. (Box Box 3)
- Lancaster, St. Clair to George Stevenson. Docket: "Sir Jno St. Clair to Mr. Stevenson Lancaster May 6th", 1758 May 5; LS (copy), 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Carlisle, Robert Callender to St. Clair. Docketed: "Mr Callender Carlisle May 6th", 1758 May 6; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Annapolis, Sharpe to Forbes. Docketed: "Govr Sharp. Annapolis May 6", 1758 May 6; LS, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Conrad Weiser. "Account of News delivered by a Indian, called Bill-Sack, and a Cayuga Indian, named Iorachquison both lately come from the Six Nation Country, taken the Sixth day of May 1758." Docketed: "Copy Indian Intelligence 6 May 1758 From Fort Augusta ", 1758 May 6; Ms (copy), 6 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, Draper S. Wood to Forbes. Docketed: "Proposals for Mr. Howell about provisions 6 May 1758", 1758 May 6; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Lancaster, St. Clair to Forbes. Docketed: "Sir Jno St Clair Lancaster. May 6th", 1758 May 6; LS, 3 p. (Box Box 3)
- New York, Abercromby to Forbes. Docketed: "Genll Abercromby N: York May 7th", 1758 May 7; LS, 3 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, "Capt. Bosomworth Bought of WB White" Docketed: "No 8 WB White", 1758 May 7; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Lancaster, St. Clair to Forbes. Docketed: "Sir Jno St. Clair Lancaster May 7th", 1758 May 7; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, Forbes to Abercromby. Docketed: "Letter to Genll Abercromby May 7th J:F:", 1758 May 7; L (copy), 3 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, "Mr. William West Bot. of Andrew Elliot by Order of Genl. Forbes." Docketed: "No 1 Andw. Elliot", 1758 May 8; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, "Mr. William West By Order of His Excellency General Forbes Bot. of McJanuaryett and McMurtie. " Docketed: "No. 9 Mc.Januarynet & Co", 1758 May 8; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, "Mr. William West By the order of Genl. Forbes Bought of Oswell Eve. " Docketed: "No. 10. Oswald Eve", 1758 May 8; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, "Mr. William West By Orders of his Excellency Genl. Forbes Bot of Hughes and Jones. " Docketed: "No 12 Hughes & Jones", 1758 May 8; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, " William West for Accott. General Forbes Bot: of John Carson. " Docketed: "No. 14 Jno. Carson", 1758 May 8; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- "General Forbes Bought of Abra. Mitchel." Docketed: "No. 15 Abrm. Mitchel" and "To Willm. West", 1758 May 8; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, " William West for accot: General Forbes Bot: of Jeremiah Warder. " Docket: "No. 17 Jera. Warder", 1758 May 8; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, "William Weast Bot. of Charles Coxe p order of Curnl. Forbus." Docket: "No. 19 Charles Coxe ", 1758 May 8; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, "Mr. William West Bought of Francis Harris & Co. by order of General Forbes." Docket: "Frans. Harris N 2", 1758 May 9; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- "Mr. William West Bot. Daniel Curry. " Docketed: "N 3 Danl. Curry", 1758 May 9; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, "Mr. William West Bot. of Philip Benezet. " Docketed: "No. 4 Philip Benezet", 1758 May 9; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, "Mr. William West Bot of Yorke & Potts by order of his Excellency General Forbes." Docketed: " York & Potts No: 5", 1758 May 9; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, " William West Bot. of John Head by order of General Forbes." Docketed: "N 6 John Head ", 1758 May 9; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, "Mr. William West By order of General Forbes Bought of Daniel Rundle. " Docket: "No 7 Dan. Rundle", 1758 May 9; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, "Mr. William West By Order of the General Bought of Saml. Neave." Docket: "No 13 Saml. Neave", 1758 May 9; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- "Mr. William West Bot. of Rob[ert]t & Amos Strettell. " Docketed: "No. 16 Robt. & Amos Strettell", 1758 May 9; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, "Capt. Bosomworth Bot. of Willm. West for the Cherokee Indians." Docket: "No. 18 Willm. West's bill", 1758 May 9; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, Bosomworth to Forbes, 1758 May 9; ALS, 4 p. (Box Box 3)
- Lancaster, St. Clair to Forbes. Docketed: "Sir Jno St. Clair Lancaster May 9th", 1758 May 9; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
  Encloses two faked army discharge forms printed at Ephrata, about which the letter is concerned.
- Philadelphia, William West. "His Excellency General Forbes to William West For Sundry Goods bought by his order for the Cherokee Indians as p the several Bills of parcels herewith deliver'd." Docketed: "Goods Bought by Mr West for the Cherokee Indians Philad: May 10th 1757 [sic]", 1758 May 10; MsS, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia. "Mr. William Weast Bot of Wm Henry By order of genrll. forbess." Docket: "No. 11. William Henry ", 1758 May 10; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia. " William West... Bot. of James & Drinker. " Docketed: "No: 20. James & Drinker ", 1758 May 10; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia. " William West... Bought of WB White." Docketed: "N 25 WB. White", 1758 May 10; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Lancaster, St. Clair to Forbes. Docketed: "Sir Jno St. Clair Lancaster May 10th", 1758 May 10; LS, 4 p. (Box Box 3)
- "Sir John St. Clair Bart in accot. with Joseph Simons ", 1758 May 10 -30; Ms, 1 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia. " William West... Bot: of Jere-miah Warder. " Docketed: "N 23. Jera. Warder", 1758 May 11; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, Forbes to Gov. Sharpe. Docketed: "Copy Letter to Govr Sharp Philad: May [12th] 1758", 1758 May 12; LS (copy), 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia. " William West Bout. of Samuel & Samuel Purviance. " Docketed: "Saml & Saml. Purviance No. 21", 1758 May 12; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, Forbes to Bosomworth. Docketed: "Copy of Genl. Forbes's Instructions 12th. May 1758", 1758 May 12; L (copy), 3 p. (Box Box 3)
- York, St. Clair to [Forbes]. Docket: "Sir Jno St. Clair. York May 12th", 1758 May 12; LS, 3 p. (Box Box 3)
- Annapolis, Sharpe to Forbes. Docketed: "Governr Sharp. Annapolis May 14th", 1758 May 14; LS, 3 p. (Box Box 3)
- (in third person) Philadelphia, Forbes to Provincial Commissioners. Docketed: "Letter to the provinciale commissrs Phi: May 14th", 1758 May 14; AL, 3 p. (Box Box 3)
- Alexandria, John Carlyle to St. Clair. Docketed on separate address leaf: "Mr Carlyle's account from Virginia ", 1758 May 14; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
  Enclosure: St. Clair account, 1756 May -1757 January. 1 p.
- Albany, Abercromby to Forbes. Docketed: "General Abercromby Albany 14th May 1758", 1758 May 14; LS, 3 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia. "Mr. William White Bought of WB White" Docketed: "No 22 WB White", 1758 May 14; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Williamsburg, John Blair to St. Clair. Docketed: "Mr. President Blairs Letter of the 15th. of May 1758", 1758 May 15; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Alexandria, Draper S. Wood to St. Clair. Docketed on separate address leaf: "comissy Woods letter from Virginia about what Mr Carlysle has in store", 1758 May 15; LS, 1 p. (Box Box 3)
  Enclosure: "A return of provisions expended from April 18th 1756 to December 1, 1757 at Alexandria..." 1 p.
- Alexandria, Draper S. Wood to Forbes. "A Return of Provisions in Store at Alexandria belonging to the Crown May 16th. 1758." Docketed: "Return of provisions at Alexandria Virginia May 16th", 1758 May 16; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- " William West Bot. of Wharton & Story. " Docketed: "N 24 Wharton & Story ", 1758 May 16; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Williamsburg, John Blair to St. Clair, Winchester. Docket: "Mr. Prest. Blairs Letter of the 16th. of May 1758", 1758 May 16; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Winchester, St. Clair. "By Sir John St. Clair Bart. Commanding at Winchester..." Docketed: "Proclamat: at Virginia by Sr Jno St clair", 1758 May 16; Ms (copy), 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Capt. Bossomworth to William Rush Dr. Docketed: "No 31 Wm. Rush", 1758 May 17; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Philadelphia, "Capt. Bosomworth Bot: of William West. " Docketed: "No 27 Wm. West's bill", 1758 May 18; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Winchester, St. Clair to John Blair. Docketed: "Copy Sir J St Clair to President Blair Winchester May 19th", 1758 May 19; L (copy), 3 p. (Box Box 3)
- Winchester, St Clair to Forbes. Docketed: "Sir Jno St Clair Indian Winchester May 19th", 1758 May 19; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Winchester, St. Clair to Forbes. Docketed: "Sir Jno St. Clair Winchester May 19th 1758", 1758 May 19; LS, 4 p. (Box Box 3)
- Charlestown, Edmund Atkin to Forbes. Docketed: "Mr Atkins Letter Charlestown May 20th", 1758 May 20; LS, 8 p. (Box Box 3)
- Williamsburg, John Blair to Forbes. Docketed: "Letter Prest. Blair Willmburgh May 20th", 1758 May 20; ALS, 3 p. (Box Box 3)
- Williamsburg, "Extract of a Letter from Mr. Prest. Blair to Lt. Colo. Mercer May 20th 1758." Docketed: "Extract Letter Presidt Blair to Colo. Mercer. Willmburgh May 20th", 1758 May 20; L (copy), 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Thomas H. Beemer, et al, "To the Head men and Warriors of the Cherokee Nation at Winchester. " On same page is ALS., Bedford, Byrd to Richard Smith, Winchester. Docketed: "Letter Col: Byrds Indians to the Cherokees at Winchester ", 1758 May 21; L (copy), 2 p. (Box Box 3)
- Bedford, Byrd to [Forbes]. Docketed: "Letter Colo. Byrd Bedford in Virginia 21st May", 1758 May 21; ALS, 3 p. (Box Box 3)
- Winchester, St. Clair to Forbes. Docketed: "Sr John St Clair Winchester 21st May 1758", 1758 May 21; LS, 4 p. (Box Box 3)
- Henry Bouquet. "Articles of Agreement made and concluded by and between of the Township of and County of in the province of Pennsylvania of the one part and Colonel Henry Bouquet..." Docketed: "The Contract for the Waggons by Colonel Bouquet", 1758 May 22; Ms, 3 p. (Box Box 4)
- Fort Loudoun, William Trent to St. Clair. Docketed: "Letter Commissary Trent to Sir John St. Clair Fort Loudoun 22d May", 1758 May 22; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 4)
- Carlisle, John Armstrong to St. Clair, Winchester. Docketed: "Letter Colo. Armstrong to Sir John St. Clair Carlisle 22d May", 1758 May 22; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 4)
- Philadelphia. " William West Bought of Mathias Bush. " Docketed: "N 26 Maths. Bush", 1758 May 22; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 4)
- " William West Bot. of Jno Ord." Docketed: "N 29 John Ord ", 1758 May 22; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 4)
- Fort Loudoun, William Trent to. Docketed: "Letter. Commissary Trent Fort Loudoun 23d May", 1758 May 23; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 4)
- Fort Loudoun, William Thompson to Bosomworth. Docketed: "Letter Capt. Thompson to Capt. Bossomworth Fort Loudoun 23d May", 1758 May 23; ALS, 2 p. (Box Box 4)
- Lancaster, Bosomworth to Forbes. Docketed: "Captain Bosomworth Lancaster 23d May 1758", 1758 May 23; ALS, 3 p. (Box Box 4)
- Philadelphia, [Forbes] to St. Clair. Docketed: "Copy Letter to Sir Jno. St. Clair Phi: May 23d 1758", 1758 May 23; L (copy), 4 p. (Box Box 4)
- "A List of Goods Sent by Willm. West to Capt. Bosomworth by Order of His Excellency General Forbes" and "A List of Goods Bot. by Captain Bosomworth & William West...", 1758 May 23; Ms, 3 p. (Box Box 4)
- Winchester, St. Clair to John Blair. Docketed: "Copy of Sir John St. Clair s Letter to the Prest. of Virginia of the 23d. of May 1758", 1758 May 23; L (copy), 4 p. (Box Box 4)
- Charlestown, Archibald Montgomery "Return of the First Highland Battalion Commanded by the Honble Colo. Arch'd Montgomery Charlestown Road 24th May 1758." Docketed: "Return of the First Highland Battalion Commanded by The Honble Colo. Archd. Montgomery Charlestown Road 24th May 1758", 1758 May 24; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 4)
- Frederick County. " Moses Stringer being Gone Express to Carlyl..." Docketed: "Declaration Moses Stringer the Express Frederick County 24th May", 1758 May 24; MsS, 2 p. (Box Box 4)
- "A list of Southern Indians ready to March." Docketed: "Indians march'd to Shippensbourg ", 1758 May 24; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 4)
- Winchester, St. Clair: "Orders for Colo.Washington Commanding the Troops of the Collony & Dominion of Virginia. " Docketed: "Orders for Colo. Washington of the 24th. of May 1758", 1758 May 24; MsS, 3 p. (Box Box 4)
- Winchester, St. Clair to [Forbes] Docketed: "Letter Sir John St Clair Winchester 24th May", 1758 May 24; ALS, 4 p. (Box Box 4)
- Philadelphia, Forbes to Sharpe. Docketed: "Copy Letter to Govr Sharp Philad: May 25th", [1758] May 25; L (copy), 3 p. (Box Box 4)
- Philadelphia, [Forbes] to Bouquet. Docketed: "Copy Letter to Colo Bouquet May 25th", 1758 May 25; L (draft), 4 p. (Box Box 4)
- Philadelphia, William West to Forbes, 1758 May 25; ALS, 1 p. (Box Box 4)
- Carlisle, Bosomworth to Forbes. Docketed: "Letter Capt. Bossomworth Carlisle, 25th May", 1758 May 25; ALS, 4 p. (Box Box 4)
- " William West to Abra: Mitchel Dr." Docketed: "No 28 Abrm. Mitchel", 1758 May 25; Ms, 2 p. (Box Box 4)
- Winchester, St. Clair to Forbes. Docketed: "Letter Sir John St. Clair Winchester 25th May", 1758 May 25; LS, 2 p. (Box Box 4)
- Williamsburg, Blair to St. Clair. Docketed: "Copy of Mr. Prest. Blairs Letter of the 25th. of May to Sir Jno. St Clair", 1758 May 25; L (copy), 3 p. (Box Box 4)